Dereck San Miguel

E-Commerce Specialist

Currently an experienced full-time E-commerce specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the consumer goods industry.

Currently enrolled in school for Full Stack Development at University of California, Irvine and a International Business graduate from University of Hawaii.



Address

Personal Info

1945 E. Kirkwood Ave.

Orange, CA 92866

Phone

(714)-488-7729

E-mail

derecksanmiguel0@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://derecksm.github.io/portfolio/index.html

GitHub

https://github.com/derecksm

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jsmith zety



HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

AJAX

JSON and REST APIs

Node.js

MySQL

React.js

Google Analytics / Data Analysis

Email Marketing

SEO Research

Photoshop



Experience

2016-08 - E-Commerce Specialist

present Incipio Group (Irvine, CA)

Duties

- Assisted in the design of product / category pages to help create a better UX
- Devised a SEO strategy to increase leads from search engine traffic to Incipio
- Implemented online marketing promotions and seasonal sales
- Presented marketing plans, strategies, and ROI of past promotions in order to create better marketing campaigns
- Tracked keyword ranking for new devices and discovered opportunities to increase SERP ranking
- Collaborated with social media influencers and media sites for link building opportunities

2015-08 - Account Manager

2016-07 Steele Logistics (City of Industry, CA)

Duties

- Handled daily operational shipping, receiving, and transportation to major retail organizations for our clients
- Managed inventory levels and the aging of product on the shelves
- Operated as the lead point of contact for our accounts
- Maintained client satisfaction by making sure their business is running efficiently and effectively

Education

University of California, Irvine, Full Stack Development,

Certificate

Learning front end and back end web development with a focus on mobile optimization, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices.

2011 - University of Hawaii, International Business, Bachelors

2015 Studied the global environment of business and how businesses must

constantly adapt to their environment to succeed across borders.

2014 University of Otago (Dunedin, New Zealand)

Studied Business Management and Marketing New Zealand while doing some personal exploration and development.

University of Sevilla (Sevilla, Spain)

Learned how to be more open-minded, appreciate a variety of different cultures, and how business operations change from place to place.